NASA的OSIRIS-REx探测器正在飞往小行星贝努
NASA's OSIRIS-REx spacecraft is heading to asteroid Bennu
再飞回来
and back
OSIRIS-REx探测器任务目标
The OSIRIS-REx mission goal is to study
是研究地球附近小行星贝努，并将其样本带回地球
near-Earth asteroid Bennu and return a sample to Earth
在2016年9月8日，OSIRIS-REx已经
OSIRIS-REx's launch window opens September 8, 2016
从佛罗里达州卡纳维拉尔角41号发射台升空
from Space Launch Complex 41 at Cape Canaveral, Florida
安置在半人马上面级的探测器
The spacecraft, nestled inside a Centaur upper stage
乘着强迫症们最爱的单助推器宇宙神5火箭发射升空
launches on an Atlas V rocket with a single solid rocket booster
火箭一级分离
The rocket's first stage separates
接着半人马上面级点火
and then the Centaur upper stage fires
然后整流罩分离
The fairings separate from the rocket
然后OSIRIS-REx探测器与半人马上面级分离
and the OSIRIS-REx spacecraft releases from the Centaur upper stage
探测器面向太阳，展开太阳帆板
Angled toward the Sun, the spacecraft deploys its solar arrays
此时速度已经超过25000英里每小时（11.18千米每秒）
Now traveling over 25,000 miles per hour
探测器逃离了地球的引力
OSIRIS-REx escapes Earth's gravity
踏上了飞往小行星贝努的旅程
and begins its cruise toward asteroid Bennu
23个月后的2018年8月
After 23 months, the spacecraft arrives at
探测器将到达小行星贝努
asteroid Bennu in August, 2018
OSIRIS-REx使用其携带的观测设备
With its suite of observational instruments
一边环绕小行星
OSIRIS-REx orbits the asteroid
一边研究它的特征，绘制表面地图
studying its characteristics and mapping its surface
四个阶段的勘探之后
After four phases of survey observations
OSIRIS-REx开始准备收集样本
OSIRIS-REx begins preparations to collect the sample
在2020年7月，多次演练与勘探之后的
In July 2020, after months of rehearsals and study
探测器开始接近小行星并采集样本
the spapcecraft approached for sample collection
它缓缓下降接近表面
It slowly descends to Bennu's surface
速度小于每小时四百米
at less than a quarter mile per hour
之后OSIRIS-REx轻轻用它的伸缩臂接触小行星表面
With an outstretched arm,OSIRIS-REx briefly touches the surface
“摸摸就走”样本采集器，简称TAGSAM
The touch-and-go sample acquisition mechanism, TAGSAM
会向表面岩石尘埃吹高压氮气
blows high-pressure nitrogen gas into the surface rocks and dust
把表面松散的物质吹进TAGSAM的头部
sending loose asteroid material up into the TAGSAM head
OSIRIS-REx把样本装进一个舱体后
OSIRIS-REx backs away from Bennu
从贝努返回地球
and stows the sample in a capsule for its journey to Earth
OSIRIS-REx离开贝努的窗口期是2021年3月
In March 2021, the window opens for OSIRIS-REx to depart Bennu
探测器将于2023年9月24日返回地球
The spacecraft returns to Earth September 24, 2023
届时样本返回舱分离
and jettisons the Sample Return Capsule
之后探测器本体再次飞离地球
As the spacecraft leaves Earth
返回舱以超过12km/s的速度进入地球大气层
and the return capsule enters the Earth's atmosphere at over 27,000 mph
当然，是在隔热罩的保护下
protected by a heat shield
距离地面几英里的地方降落伞打开
A couple miles above the surface, a parachute deploys
之后返回舱在犹他州沙漠里软着陆
and the capsule lands softly in the Utah desert
未来几十年内，贝努的秘密终将揭开
Bennu's secrets can now be investigated for decades to come